A Guide to the Constituent Correspondence of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1993-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Consituent Correspondence of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1993-1997
The Library of Virginia
35717
127.35 cubic feet (128 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1994-1998: Allen)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
These records are open for research but it may be necessary for an archivist to review certain files before they can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies of the records can be made. Privacy protected and other protected information is considered confidential and restricted from public access for 75 years. If you are planning to use these records, please contact Archives Reference Services for additional details before planning your research trip.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Georgia Root, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth, Richmond, Virginia, 13 February 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Office of Constituent Affairs was first established in 1984 to serve as a liaison between the Governor and the citizens of the Commonwealth. The office received and replied to mail directed to the Governor from citizens of the commonwealth, political officials, and organizations.
George Felix Allen was born March 8, 1952 in Whittier, California to famed NFL football coach George H. Allen and his wife Henrietta (Lumbroso) Allen. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 and the University of Virginia School of Law in 1977. Allen served in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982-1991 and served a short term in the U.S. House of Delegates in the early 1990s. In November 1993, Allen beat Attorney General Mary Sue Terry to become Governor. Governor Allen served until January 1998 and was succeeded by Governor James S. Gilmore. Governor Allen has been married to Susan (Brown) Allen since 1986 and they have three children, Forrest, Tyler, and Brooke. The family resides in Mount Vernon, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains correspondence from constituents to Governor George Allen and an attached copy of the response from the Governor or the appropriate Secretary or state department. The Office of Constituent Affairs handled the governor's constituent correspondence by directing the mail to the appropriate official(s) for response. The general correspondence found here contains invitations, requests for assistance, and inquiries about the Governor's stance on certain policy issues. Also included are letters from federal and state agencies, local government officials, Virginia General Assembly members, members of the U.S. Congress, and others, including the U.S. President, governors of other states and ambassadors. Files containing letters related to particular subjects such as the execution of Joseph O'Dell, opposition to a horse racing track in New Kent County, and those containing letters from a group of habitual writers can be found at the end of the general correspondence.
A smaller subsection of the constituent correspondence includes mail related to specific legislative actions. The legislative mail consists mainly of signed petitions and form letters, but also includes some correspondence. Legislative topics include: the Administrative License Revocation Law, parole abolition, regulation of registered dieticians, the Water Quality Monitoring and Restoration Act, patental notification, access to pollution permit decisions, seatbelt law, the Pharmacy Freedom Act, gun control, interstate waste, and the riverboat gambling referendum.
Arrangement
Constituent correspondence is divided into two sections: general correspondence and legislative correspondence. Each section is arranged in loose chronological order.
Contents List
- Constituent Correspondence (General).
  - 1993 November. (Box 1a)
  - 1993 December. (Box 1a; 1)
  - 1994 January. (Box 1-2)
  - 1994 February. (Box 2-3)
  - 1994 March. (Box 4-6)
  - 1994 April. (Box 6-7)
  - 1994 May. (Box 8-9)
  - 1994 June. (Box 10-11)
  - 1994 July. (Box 11-12)
  - 1994 August. (Box 12-13)
  - 1994 September. (Box 14-15)
  - 1994 October. (Box 15-17)
  - 1994 November. (Box 17-18)
  - 1994 December. (Box 18-20)
  - 1995 January. (Box 20-24)
  - 1995 February. (Box 24-27)
  - 1995 March. (Box 27-29)
  - 1995 April. (Box 30-32)
  - 1995 May. (Box 32-34)
  - 1995 June. (Box 34-36)
  - 1995 July. (Box 38-39)
  - 1995 August. (Box 39-41)
  - 1995 September. (Box 41-43)
  - 1995 October. (Box 43-45)
  - 1995 November. (Box 45-47)
  - 1995 December. (Box 47-48)
  - 1996 January. (Box 49-50)
  - 1996 February. (Box 50-52)
  - 1996 March. (Box 52-54)
  - 1996 April. (Box 54-56)
  - 1996 May. (Box 57-58)
  - 1996 June. (Box 59-61)
  - 1996 July. (Box 61-62)
  - 1996 August. (Box 63-64)
  - 1996 September. (Box 64-66)
  - 1996 October. (Box 66-68)
  - 1996 November. (Box 68-69)
  - 1996 December. (Box 70-71)
  - 1997 January. (Box 71-73)
  - 1997 February. (Box 73-74)
  - 1997 March. (Box 75-76)
  - 1997 April. (Box 78-81)
  - 1997 May. (Box 81-84)
  - 1997 June. (Box 84-86)
  - 1997 July. (Box 87-88)
  - 1997 August. (Box 89-90)
  - 1997 September. (Box 90-92)
  - 1997 October. (Box 93-94)
  - 1997 November. (Box 94-96)
  - 1997 December. (Box 96)
  - Habitual Writers, 1994-1997. (Box 97)
  - New Kent County Horse Race Track Opposition, 1995. (Box 98)
  - Joseph O'Dell Execution Opposition, 1996-1997. (Box 99-101)
  - Mark C. Poe Petitions for Execution, 1997. (Box 102)
- Constituent Correspondence (Legislative).
  - Administrative License Revocation Law, 1993-1994. (Box 103)
  - Registered Dieticians (HB 312), 1994. (Box 103-104)
  - Parental Notification (SB 610), 1994. (Box 105-106)
  - Parental Notification (HB 1420), 1995. (Box 106)
  - Parental Notification, 1997. (Box 107)
  - Water Quality Monitoring, Information and Restoration Act (SB 1122), 1997. (Box 107)
  - Access to Court Pollution Permit Decisions (HB 1412), 1996. (Box 108)
  - Seatbelts for Children between 4 and 16 (SB 971), 1997. (Box 108)
  - Parole Abolition, 1994. (Box 109-116)
  - Pharmacy Freedom Act (HB 840), 1994. (Box 117)
  - Gun Control (HB 2490 and SB 944), 1997. (Box 118)
  - Personal Protection Act (SB 744), 1995. (Box 118)
  - Interstate Waste, 1997. (Box 119)
  - Riverboat Gambling Referendum, 1994. (Box 120-127)